(サイ)そんな 彼のことを
キミは どうして…？
For a guy like him,
why are you...?
Why are you trying
to get him back...
どうして
あの 大蛇丸に刃向かってまで…➡
going so far as to oppose Orochimaru
and put your life at risk?
命を かけてまで
連れ戻そうとするんだ？
Why is that? When nobody's
ordering you to do so?
なぜなんだ…？
誰に 命令されているわけでも
ないのに…。
Sasuke is...
(ナルト)サスケは…➡
my friend.
オレの友達だ…。
It's a special bond
I was finally able to make.
やっと できた…➡
大切な つながりだ…。
A bond?
つながり…!?
だからって…➡
Even so...
Even so, with Orochimaru
as your opponent...
だからって 大蛇丸を相手に…。
It doesn't matter
who the opponent is!
相手が 誰だろうと
関係ねえってばよ！
If my arms get torn off,
I'll kick him down.
腕が もがれりゃ… 蹴り倒す！
If my legs get torn off,
I'll bite him down.
脚が もがれりゃ… 噛み倒す！
If my head gets torn off,
I'll stare him down.
首が もがれりゃ… にらみ倒す！
If my eyes get torn out,
I'll curse him in my grave!
目が もがれりゃ… 呪い倒す！
Even if I get chopped up
into pieces...
たとえ バラバラにされようが…➡
I'll take Sasuke back
from Orochimaru!
オレは 大蛇丸から…➡
サスケを
奪い返してやるんだってばよ！
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
Something
Important
We'll go after
I create the guard.
(ヤマト)見張りを作ったら 行くよ。
I thought we'd completely
given our pursuers the slip...
(カブト)尾行は 完全に まいたと
思ったんだけどね…。
I guess I should say...
(カブト)
さすがは 大蛇丸様の実験体…➡
I'd expect no less from
Orochimaru-sama's test subject...
といったところでしょうか…。
フッ…。
くっ… カブト…！
Kabuto...!
You're sure persistent!
(サクラ)しつこいわね！
フン…。
Sai...
サイ…。
Judging from your condition,
it appears you've been captured.
その様子からすると
キミは 捕まったようだね？
Don't interfere.
ジャマすんな！
If you do...
ジャマするっていうんなら…
容赦は しねえ！
I won't go easy on you!
It's futile.
ムダだ！
We won't
know that until we try!
ムダか どうかは…！
やってみるまで
わかんねえだろうが!!
- We won't let you interfere!
ぜってえ ジャマは させねえ!!
You've got it wrong.
違う。
I'm not talking about that.
そっちの話じゃない…。
(ヤマト)フンッ！
はぁぁぁ～っ!!
おりゃぁ～っ!!
Aha...! This is impressive...
はっ…。 コイツは すごい…。
I guess with three against one,
the odds are against me, huh?
《さすがに ３対１では
分が悪いか…》
And it appears they've got luck
on their side as well...
《カブト : 運も 向こうに
ついているようだ》
I'll believe you...
裏切ったわけじゃ
なさそうだから➡
since it doesn't appear
you've betrayed us.
ここは 信じよう。
Man, it's truly pathetic
watching you guys.
まったく アンタたちを見てると
ホントに哀れだよ。
特に ナルト君…。
You in particular, Naruto-kun.
キミを見ているとね。
Watching you...
What I mean is, it's futile even
if you were able to beat me...
(カブト)たとえ ボクを倒せたとしても
ムダだということだよ。
人は 変わる。
People change...
Sasuke-kun isn't
the old Sasuke-kun anymore.
サスケ君は もう
昔のサスケ君じゃ ないんだよ。
なっ…!?
Wha--?!
What's the idea...?
どういうつもりだ？
I used to really hate Sasuke.
((昔… オレは サスケのことが
大っ嫌いだった。
But it was actually fun
being with him.
でも 一緒にいて ホントは
すごく楽しかったんだってばよ。
アイツは…。
He's...
He's the person who acknowledged me
more than anyone else.
アイツは 誰よりも
オレのことを認めてくれた一人だ。
サスケは オレの友達だ。
Sasuke is... my friend.
It's a special bond
I was finally able to make.
(やっとできた
大切な つながりだ))
Your mission
was supposed to be...
(カブト)キミの任務は 大蛇丸様と
ダンゾウのパイプ役になること…➡
to become the liaison for Danzo
and Orochimaru-sama.
だったはず…。
People change...
(サイ)人は 変わる…。
Then the same goes for me.
(サイ)なら ボクもそうだ。
(カブト)なに？
What?!
But there are things
that don't change...
(サイ)でも 変わらないものもある。
サイ… お前…。
Sai... You...
Bonds...
つながり…。
それを 確かめてみたいんだ。
I want to see for myself...
サイ…。
Sai...
(ヤマト)サイ そのまま 捕まえてなよ。
Keep a hold on him...
(ヤマト)ムン！
くっ…！
サイ… お前 いったい 何考えて…。
Sai... What the hell
are you thinking?
キミは なぜ そこまで サスケ君との
つながりに こだわるのか…。
Why are you so hung up
on your bonds with Sasuke...
and what are those bonds?
その
つながり ってのが何なのか…？
知りたくなってね。
I want to know...
From your viewpoint,
キミたちから見たら ボクも
兄さんとのつながり ってのを➡
it seems I can't erase my
bond with my brother...
消せないでいるらしい。
((あなたが その本を
手放したくない理由…。
The reason why you don't want
to part with that book...
それは 弟としての自分を
捨てることができないでいるから。
is that you can't forsake yourself
as a younger brother...
あなたにとっては それだけ
お兄さんとのつながりが➡
It's because your bonds with
your older brother...
were that important to you!
大切だったからよ！
((あなたは
お兄さんとのつながりを➡
You don't want to erase the bonds
you have with your older brother.
消したくないと思ってる。
Bonds...
(つながり…))
If it's something
that important to me,
(サイ)ボクにとって それが
そんなに大切なものなら➡
キミとサスケ君のつながりを見れば➡
then I might understand
if I see your bonds with Sasuke.
何かが わかるかもしれない…。
そう思っただけさ。
I just thought that way.
What's so funny?!
なにがおかしいの！
You guys don't know
the real Sasuke-kun...
キミたちは 本当のサスケ君を知らない。
Where's Sasuke?
サスケは どこにいる？
Answer me.
答えるんだ。
He's probably done
with his training right about now...
(カブト)今ごろ 修業を終えて➡
and is in a room deeper
inside the hideout.
更に奥の部屋にいるだろう。
It's true that Sasuke-kun was
training with Orochimaru.
サスケ君が大蛇丸と
修業していたのは本当だ。
今の話はウソじゃないと思う。
I don't think what
he said just now is a lie.
よし… じゃあ すぐにでも…。
ただ…。
All right!
Then let's get right to it--
However...
奥の部屋といわれても…。
Where exactly is
this room deeper inside...?
I don't know, either.
ボクにだってわからないよ。
ここでは いくつもの部屋が
バラバラに並んでいる。
There are several rooms
scattered about in here.
奥の部屋といっても
１つや２つじゃない。
A room deeper inside doesn't
mean just one or two rooms...
だったら…。
In that case!
We just have to search
every single one of them!
片っ端から捜すだけだ。
そうだね…。
You're right.
手当たり次第に調べれば
見つかるかもね。
You might find it
if you search at random.
ただ… ヘタをすると…➡
However...
You could stir up
a serpent's nest.
藪をつついて
蛇を出しかねないよ。
That's also where Orochimaru-sama's
private room is, you see.
(カブト)大蛇丸様の居室も
そこにあるからね。
Thanks for speaking honestly.
正直に話してくれて
ありがとうよ。
いや… 礼には及ばないよ。
No need to thank me.
我々が 返り討ちにあうと？
Are you saying the tables
will be turned on us...?
あぁ…。
Yeah.
You jerk!
このやろう…！
それこそ
やってみるまで わからないよ。
That's something we won't know
until we try.
(ヤマト)いくぞ。
Let's go.
We won't know
until we try... huh?
やってみるまで わからない… か。
Truly... pathetic...
(カブト)ホント 哀れだねぇ…。
Now we're going to split up
and search for Sasuke.
ここからは二手に分かれて
サスケを捜す。
ボクとサクラ。
Me and Sakura on one team.
ナルトとサイの ２チームだ。
Naruto and Sai on the other.
うん わかったってばよ。
Right! Got it.
何かあったら チャクラを練るんだ。
If something comes up,
build up your Chakra.
それだけで すぐに駆けつける。
I'll rush in right away
just with that.
《サスケ…》
Sasuke...
(ヤマト)よし いくぞ！
All right!
Let's go!
《待ってろよ サスケ…。
Hang on, Sasuke!
今 オレが行くからな！》
I'm coming now!
((サスケ : ほらよ！))
Here.
((なんて顔してやがんだよ…。
Wh-What's with that... look...
you... total... loser...
(この… うすらとんかち…))
((テメエ！ なに
かっこつけてんだってばよ!!
You jerk! What're you trying
to look good for, you idiot?!
バカ！ サクラちゃんが
こんなに心配して…。
Sakura-chan's this worried about...
Naruto.
ナルト…。
(オレは お前とも戦いたい))
I want to fight you...
((オレにとって お前は 最も…。
For me, you've become...
(親しい友になった))
my closest friend.
《サスケ…》
Sasuke...!
((サクラ…。
Sakura...
(ありがとう…))
Thanks...
《サスケ君…》
Sasuke-kun...
(サイ)ナルト君…。
Naruto-kun!
あぁ！
Right!
(サイ)誰もいないようだね。
It looks like nobody's here.
(サクラ)ここじゃないわ。
This isn't the place.
ここでもねえってばよ！
Not here, either!
ここにもいないわ！
He's not here, either.
いない！
He's not here!
いないわ！
He's not here.
クソッ！
Damn it!
《サクラ : サスケ君…。
Sasuke-kun...
どこにいるの？》
Where are you?!
どこだ？
《私たち ようやく
ここまで来たのよ！》
We've... finally made it this far!
《どこなんだ!?》
Where are you?!
《サスケ君！》
Sasuke-kun...!
サスケ～！
Sasuke!
The clouds
drift accross
a distant sky,
The clouds
drift accross
a distant sky,
sora wa haruka
kumo wa nagarete
Far, far, far away,
beyond the horizon.
tooku tooku tooku
ni kogaretemo
Where will I go
from here and
what do I want?
Where will I go
from here and
what do I want?
doko o mezashite boku
wa fumidasu no ka
It's time to break
through my
fears and doubts.
It's time to break
through my
fears and doubts.
mayoi o ima
furikitte
Even though
I have a destiny
that I can't
escape from,
Even though
I have a destiny
that I can't
escape from,
nigeba no nai
unmei demo
I'm searching
for tomorrow.
asu o sagashite
Because the bonds
of friendship
keep me strong.
Because the bonds
of friendship
keep me strong.
boku o tsuyoku
suru no wa
nakama no kizuna
boku o tsuyoku
suru no wa
nakama no kizuna
Awaken the wild
side and let loose
the feelings!
Awaken the wild
side and let loose
the feelings!
mezamero yasei
afuredashita
kanjou
mezamero yasei
afuredashita
kanjou
Hidden within
my heart as I
smile recklessly.
Hidden within
my heart as I
smile recklessly.
mune ni himete
gamushara
no egao de
mune ni himete
gamushara
no egao de
And it's only when
I shout that the
truth is echoed.
And it's only when
I shout that the
truth is echoed.
sakebigoe wa
woah woah
shinjitsu dake
hibiku darou
sakebigoe wa
woah woah
shinjitsu dake
hibiku darou
(ヤマト)第２回 木ノ葉縦断スーパークイズ！
My heart burns
and I'll hold on
to your hand.
My heart burns
and I'll hold on
to your hand.
kokoro moyase
soshite te o
tsunagou
kokoro moyase
soshite te o
tsunagou
今日のパネラーは この方たちです！
ぜってえ当ててやる！
If we're gonna
pursue those
eternal desires.
If we're gonna
pursue those
eternal desires.
yume ni
kometa eien
no negai o
yume ni
kometa eien
no negai o
負けないわよ！
Your prayer will
be granted,
motomeru nara
woah woah
それでは 中忍試験編からの
早押しクイズ！
Because the light
you seek lies there.
sagashiteru
hikari wa kitto
soko ni aru sa
sagashiteru
hikari wa kitto
soko ni aru sa
中忍選抜 第１の試験で
試験官を務めた➡
拷問と尋問のプロ…。
森野 イビキ！
(ヤマト)ですが 第２の試験➡
Awaken the
beast within!
mezamero
yasei
死の森での巻物争奪戦で
試験官を務めた超甘党の…。
Hmph,
It's you...
At last,
they meet again.
Finally.
Next Episode
みたらし アンコ！
Naruto-kun, we're split up
into two teams.
(ヤマト)ですが
大蛇丸からの命を受け➡
You should rest a little...
音隠れから参戦していた
３人組の名は？
Shut up! I can't be resting
at a time like this.
いたいた
コイツら なんて名前だっけ？
We're almost to Sasuke...
覚えてない。
(ブザー)
(ヤマト)タイムアップ！
Man, you're certainly talkative,
you lose your head...
(ヤマト)正解は ドス ザク キン！
and you have no manners.
(ヤマト)サイさん お見事！
Mind your own business!
(ヤマト)ちなみに その後
ドスは 我愛羅の餌食に…。
You really resemble him.
(ヤマト)ザクとキンは
大蛇丸の 穢土転生の生け贄に➡
Resemble who?
My brother.
利用されました！
The Picture Book's Story
Next time: "The Picture Book's Story"
こういうときは笑っていいのかな。
(ナルト/サクラ)笑うな！
Leaf Village Trivia Super Quiz, Part 2!
Here are our contestants for today!
I'm gonna win this time!
I'm not going to lose!
Now then, here's a quiz from
the Chunin Exam arc!
The proctor for the first test in the Chunin Exams
was also a pro at torture and interrogation-
Morino Ibiki!
And! There was the proctor for the survival test
in the Forest of Death, who loves sweets-
Mitarashi Anko!
And! There were three Sound Ninja who were obeying
orders from Orochimaru. What were their names?
Oh, yeah... What were their names again...?
I don't remember...
Time's up!
The correct answer is, "Dosu, Zaku and Kin"!
Well done, Sai-san!
For the record, Dosu fell prey to Gaara.
Zaku and Kin were used as sacrifices so Orochimaru
could use the Impure World Resurrection
Should I smile at a time like this?
- Hell no!
「息子へ。 拝啓
お体かわりございませんか？
私は おかげさまで元気ですが
近頃 生活に変化がありました。
私の住まいに
ルームメートがやってきたことです。
この男 極悪人か
はたまた ただのバカなのか。
ただひとつ言えることは→
私が今もこうして
手紙を書いていられるのは→
あの男のおかげだということです。